modernhiker.com 2014-12-03

# Privacy Policy | Modern Hiker

**We collect personal and activity data, which may be linked.**

 ****

**** We use technologies like cookies (small files stored on your browser), web beacons, or unique device identifiers to identify your computer or device so we can deliver a better experience. Our systems also log information like your browser, operating system and IP address.

We also may collect personally identifiable information that you provide to us, such as your name, address, phone number or email address. With your permission, we may also access other personal information on your device, such as your phone book, calendar or messages, in order to provide services to you. If authorized by you, we may also access profile and other information from services like Facebook.

Our systems may associate this personal information with your activities in the course of providing service to you (such as pages you view or things you click on or search for).

We do not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. If you believe we have inadvertently collected such information, please contact us so we can promptly obtain parental consent or remove the information.

**We collect or share your location only with permission.**

 ****

**** In serving you, we may use or store your precise geographic location, if you give us permission to do so. We do not use or share this data for any other purpose. Many devices will indicate through an icon when location services are operating. We only share this location information with others as approved by you.

**You can request to see your personal data.**

 ****

**** You can sign into your account to see any personally identifiable information we have stored, such as your name, email, address or phone number. You can also contact us by email to request to see this information.

**We may keep data indefinitely.**

 ****

**** We may keep data indefinitely.

**We don’t share your personal data with other companies.**

 ****

**** We generally do not share personally identifiable information (such as name, address, email or phone) with other companies.

**Ad companies collect anonymous data. You can opt out.**

 ****

**** Ad companies may use and collect anonymous data about your interests to customize content and advertising here and in other sites and applications. Interest and location data may be linked to your device, but is not linked to your identity. Click to see company privacy policies and opt-out choices:

Google

Google (www.google.com) operates the Google Display Network (comprising partner websites and some Google properties like YouTube), DoubleClick online ad serving products and the DoubleClick Ad Exchange, and Invite Media. These provide advertisers with the tools needed to plan, execute and analyze marketing programs with greater ease and efficiency, while enabling publishers to maximize their returns from online advertising. Note: Because Google uses DoubleClick and Invite technology, cookies placed by Google for behavioral advertising, including the opt out cookie, will appear as DoubleClick and Invite cookies.

**You can ask privacy questions.**

 ****

**** If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policies, please contact us http://modernhiker.com/about

**Service providers access data on our behalf.**

 ****

**** In order to serve you, we may share your personal and anonymous information with other companies, including vendors and contractors. Their use of information is limited to these purposes, and subject to agreements that require them to keep the information confidential. Our vendors provide assurance that they take reasonable steps to safeguard the data they hold on our behalf, although data security cannot be guaranteed.

Analytics companies may access anonymous data (such as your IP address or device ID) to help us understand how our services are used. They use this data solely on our behalf. They do not share it except in aggregate form; no data is shared as to any individual user. Click to see company privacy policies that govern their use of data.

Google Analytics

Google Analytics is a web analytics tool that helps website owners understand how visitors engage with their website. Google Analytics customers can view a variety of reports about how visitors interact with their website so they can improve it. Google Analytics collects information anonymously. It reports website trends without identifying individual visitors.

**We take steps to protect personal information**

 ****

**** We take reasonable steps to secure your personally identifiable information against unauthorized access or disclosure. We encrypt transmission of data on pages where you provide payment information. However, no security or encryption method can be guaranteed to protect information from hackers or human error.

Information we collect may be stored or processed on computers located in any country where we do business.

**Special situations may require disclosure of your data.**

 ****

**** To operate the service, we also may make identifiable and anonymous information available to third parties in these limited circumstances: (1) with your express consent, (2) when we have a good faith belief it is required by law, (3) when we have a good faith belief it is necessary to protect our rights or property, or (4) to any successor or purchaser in a merger, acquisition, liquidation, dissolution or sale of assets. Your consent will not be required for disclosure in these cases, but we will attempt to notify you, to the extent permitted by law to do so.

**You can review more privacy-related information.**

 ****

**** This privacy policy was last updated on February 10, 2014. Our privacy policy may change from time to time. If we make any material changes to our policies, we will place a prominent notice on our website or application. If the change materially affects registered users, we will send a notice to you by email, push notification or text.

Last Updated: Monday, February 10, 2014
